<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Joseph Dykstra&apos;s Blog</title>
        <description>Follow Joseph&apos;s opinions on your feed reader!</description>
        <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 04:23:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <title>Joseph Dykstra&apos;s Blog</title>
            <url>http://josephdykstra.com/logo.png</url>
            <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>Copyright © Joseph Dykstra 2015.</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My First Post]]></title>
            <link>http://josephdykstra.com/my-first-post.md</link>
            <guid>http://josephdykstra.com/my-first-post.md</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>First post.</p>
<p>You can put this blog on Feedly or another RSS feed reader. Feed Readers are the best things since the interwebs. (OK, maybe not.)</p>
<p>I will probably express feelings on what I believe on somewhat controversial topics. I hope to post my opinions on Music, Dancing, What Time a Day Begins, and anything else that I feel is worthy. Hopefully I am able to present you with a logical and biblical perspective.</p>
<p>You should check out <a href="http://rebeccasscatteredscribblings.blogspot.com/">Rebecca's Blog</a>, <a href="http://trueandfaithfulwords.wordpress.com/">Laura's Blog</a>, <a href="http://joshduff.com/">Josh's Blog</a>, and <a href="http://cougarlane.com/_/The_Race_Blog/The_Race_Blog.html">Jarrod's Blog</a>.</p>
<p>I might post twice a day, or twice a year, and that is why feed readers are so nice. You add 10 blogs, it gathers the data, you read it on your own schedule, you don't need 10 bookmarks for your 10 favorite blogs.</p>
]]></description>
            <content:encoded/>
            <author>
                <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
                <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Music]]></title>
            <link>http://josephdykstra.com/music.md</link>
            <guid>http://josephdykstra.com/music.md</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Music. We are surrounded by it; MP3 Players, Radios, Bands. Music played at public places is usually pagan except around Christmas time. The first time you hear anything about music is, I believe, Genesis 4:21. The people at my orthodontist's office were playing the most horrendous screeching-singing music that I've heard for a long time.</p>
<p>I mainly listen to Christian (and instrumental) music. But I don't really care much for, Casting Crowns, even though what they say is (mostly) great. I personally like Christian Hip Hop (CHH) like 116 Clique, Lecrae, Flame, etc.</p>
<p>Casting Crowns and Lecrae are both Christian, but have different styles. They both reference the same faults/needs of today's culture. For example: environmentalism.</p>
<p>Casting Crowns in <em>While You were Sleeping</em> says "United States of America ... save[s] the trees and kill[s] the children..."</p>
<p>Lecrae in <em>Blow your High</em> says "... worshiping a tree instead of worshiping the King..."</p>
<p>I like the style of rap, but I like rock too, some other styles are cool too.</p>
<p>Music can be something people listen to way too much, or not the right kind. It shapes how you feel as you listen, and maybe for long periods of time; sort of how certain lighting makes a movie creepy, and if you watch too many creepy movies it does not help how you act.</p>
<p>If I listen to Relient K, Sanctus Real, Switchfoot, Skillet, and the like, for about 0.75 hours or more, I start getting a bit depressed, dreary, and quite sick of it. If I listen to one style for 1.5 hours or more I get really sick of it.</p>
<p>I think the music you hear might change you more than you'd think.</p>
]]></description>
            <content:encoded/>
            <author>
                <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
                <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intellectual Property]]></title>
            <link>http://josephdykstra.com/intellectual-property.md</link>
            <guid>http://josephdykstra.com/intellectual-property.md</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Intellectual Property is the philosophy that thoughts, ideas, sounds, sights, etc. are owned by the person who first conceived/made them. Intellectual property is non-physical  including, but is not limited to: musical, literary, and artistic works, discoveries, inventions, and words, phrases, symbols, and designs.</p>
<p>The aforementioned intangible objects are protected under copyrights, trademarks, patents, and more.</p>
<p>Infringements on copyrights are often, considered stealing, partially due to propaganda spread by video marketing companies, like this video:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/HmZm8vNHBSU&amp;fs=1&amp;source=uds"></iframe>
<p>The Christian's (and the movie's) main argument against "piracy" that it "is stealing". If I go to wal-mart, take a CD and run out with out paying, I am stealing the CD. If I torrent the data from the CD, then I am not taking a tangible object, therefore I am not stealing. If I paint a picture, and someone takes it from my house, they're stealing. If they takes a photograph of it, and then they print it, they are not stealing.</p>
<p>The Christian's second argument is sometimes "A worker is worthy of his wages." Just because I paint a picture that is, to my perspective, very beautimous, does not mean that I am entitled to someone's buying it. If someone does buy it though, it belongs to them.</p>
<p>And if you are and atheist or the like, then I don't see why you would have any conscience issues doing anything, because you have little reason to be "moral", except the government's laws and social peer pressure.</p>
<p>I am not saying that you should "pirate" whatever. I am stating the belief that intellectual property is bogus, and "pirating" is not theft.</p>
]]></description>
            <content:encoded/>
            <author>
                <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
                <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jokes]]></title>
            <link>http://josephdykstra.com/jokes.md</link>
            <guid>http://josephdykstra.com/jokes.md</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Disclaimer: I am not referencing Batman: The Dark Knight in this post.</p>
<p>One thing I have noted with many unkind jokes, is that they are based on something mean that the joker thinks.</p>
<p>What if I thought Seth's hair was awful when he dyed it? (My bro, for a play, 2012)</p>
<p>I could have said "Seth, your hair is horrendous. Just kidding." The "joke" would have been based on truth.</p>
<p>Bob is pitching to Tom who is batting, and Tom thinks, "he is not very good at pitching." It could be easy for Tom to say, "you should take pitching lessons from me... Kidding!" Or Tom might sarcastically say "You're good at pitching."</p>
<p>The previous insults are based on truth, which not only hurts the receiver more, but also tells what the joker is thinking. In the case of sarcasm though, usually the statement is opposite of the thought. When I see it, I wonder how often I do the same.</p>
<p>If our lives were fully centered around following in Christ's footsteps, then how different would our jokes be?</p>
]]></description>
            <content:encoded/>
            <author>
                <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
                <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ECD Part 2: Kilts]]></title>
            <link>http://josephdykstra.com/ecd-part-2-kilts.md</link>
            <guid>http://josephdykstra.com/ecd-part-2-kilts.md</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><strong>Deuteronomy 22:5</strong></p>
<p>A woman shall not wear anything that pertains to a man, nor shall a man put on a woman's garment, for all who do so are an abomination to the Lord your God.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the US, skirts, dresses, and the like, are considered a woman's garments.</p>
<p>A kilt probably is not cross-dressing. I feel that it is somewhat border lined.</p>
<p>Why I would not wear one:</p>
<ol>
<li>I don't know if it is morally ok.</li>
<li>They look silly.</li>
<li>I'm Dutch, not Scottish.</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <content:encoded/>
            <author>
                <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
                <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
            </author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>