<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Joseph Dykstra&apos;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://josephdykstra.com</link>
    <updated>2016-08-03T00:31:38Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
        <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
        <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://josephdykstra.com"/>
    <subtitle>Follow Joseph&apos;s opinions on your feed reader!</subtitle>
    <logo>http://josephdykstra.com/logo.png</logo>
    <rights>Copyright © Joseph Dykstra 2015.</rights>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Voting for Trump is a Morally Bad Choice]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/short-wayne-grudem-refutation</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/short-wayne-grudem-refutation">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-08-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was going to read <a href="http://www.thegreatfiction.com/2016/07/30/the-moral-case-for-donald-trump-refuted/">a refutation</a> to Wayne Grudem's article about voting for Trump, but then I saw the dreaded "wall of text". The small scrollbar whispered, "Is this really how you want to spend your time?"  And so instead of reading a few paragraphs, I decided to see if I can construct a shorter refutation.</p>
<p>In Wayne Grudem's article, <em><a href="http://townhall.com/columnists/waynegrudem/2016/07/28/why-voting-for-donald-trump-is-a-morally-good-choice-n2199564">Why Voting for Donald Trump Is a Morally Good Choice</a></em>, under the <em>A good candidate with flaws</em> section, he states:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I do not think that voting for Donald Trump is a morally evil choice because there is nothing morally wrong with voting for a <em>flawed</em> candidate if you think he will do more good for the nation than his opponent. In fact, it is the morally right thing to do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the Bible, there are minimal requirements for rulers:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=2+Samuel+23%3A3&amp;version=NKJV">2 Samuel 23:3</a><br>
He who rules over men must be just, Ruling in the fear of God.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(See longer post by Phillip Kayser about <a href="https://www.facebook.com/philkayser/posts/10157270314665311">minimal requirements for rulers</a>.)</p>
<p>Does Trump fear God? I believe the answer is a definite "no".</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href>John 14:12,15</a><br>
"Most assuredly, I say to you, he who believes in Me, the works that I do he will do also; and greater works than these he will do, because I go to My Father.</p>
<p>If you love Me, keep My commandments.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Trump does not lead a Godly life, nor does he claim to. Trump is unfit for office, according to God's word.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Vote For a Candidate That Can't Win]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/a-vote-for-a-candidate-that-cant-win</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/a-vote-for-a-candidate-that-cant-win">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-08-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you heard this?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A vote for a candidate that has no chance of winning is a vote for the majority.</p>
<p>— Facebook Comment</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am not convinced that a vote for a candidate that can't win is a vote for the leader (a.k.a. "majority"). I've decided to run the numbers.</p>
<hr>
<p>Let's imagine that there are 10,000 voters, not including you:</p>
<ul>
<li>4500 are voting for Candidate Clam Chowder</li>
<li>4000 are voting for Kandidate Ketchup</li>
<li>1500 are voting for Candidate Creamy Cool Whip</li>
</ul>
<p>You are a supporter of Candidate Creamy Cool Whip, and you strongly <em>distaste</em> Cadidate Clam Chowder. You're not a fan of Kandidate Ketchup, but "Ketchup is a bit better than Clam Chowder", you tell yourself.</p>
<p>Election day is coming up, and the Ketchuppers say that if you don't vote for Kandidate Ketchup, you're voting for Candidate Clam Chowder.</p>
<p>Here are the two scenarios:</p>
<ol>
<li>You give in the demands, and cast your vote for Ketchup</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Clam Chowder: 4500 votes</li>
<li>Ketchup: 4001 votes</li>
<li>Creamy Cool Whip: 1500 votes</li>
</ul>
<ol start="2">
<li>You say "deal with it!" to the Ketchuppers, and you stand with your fellow Cool Whippers</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Clam Chowder: 4500 votes</li>
<li>Ketchup: 4000 votes</li>
<li>Creamy Cool Whip: 1501 votes</li>
</ul>
<p>As you can see, I just ran the numbers; feel free to double-check them. In each scenarios, Clam Chowder had the same number of votes: 4500. It is clear that a vote for Creamy Cool Whip was not a vote for Clam Chowder. You know what <em>is</em> a vote for Clam Chowder? Voting for Clam Chowder.</p>
<p>The Ketchuppers are attemting to get your vote. Are you comprimising your morals if you give it to them?</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Podcast Apps Review]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/android-podcast-apps-review</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/android-podcast-apps-review">
        </link>
        <updated>2016-03-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a fan of podcasts, and I recently purchased an android phone. I needed an app to handle podcasts for me. I have a few requirements for a podcast app:</p>
<ol>
<li>I want the app to automatically download the episodes from oldest to newest</li>
<li>I want the app to delete the listened episodes</li>
<li>I want the UI to be simple, and intuitive</li>
</ol>
<p>I tried 4 well-rated apps: AntennaPod, Podcast Republic, Podkicker, and Podcast Addict</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Disclaimer: Facts such as ratings and features of apps might change after I write this review.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>AntennaPod</h2>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.danoeh.antennapod">AntennaPod</a> is rated 4.5 stars on the google play store. It is ad-free and open source.</p>
<p>The UI is great. It is simple, intuitive, and I like how it is set up.</p>
<p>It does have an auto-download, and auto-delete. However, it doesn't support downloading from oldest to newest, so it's out.</p>
<h2>Podcast Republic</h2>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.itunestoppodcastplayer.app&amp;hl=en">Podcast Republic</a> is rated 4.4 stars on the google play store. It is ad-supported.</p>
<p>The UI is beautiful. The app feel like it was created by a designer; it acts in non-android-standard ways. This makes it less intuitive, but allows the app to be cleaner. This app is a bit confusing with the many screens it has.</p>
<p>Lots of settings for this app, but they're well organized, so you can easily find the setting you're looking for.</p>
<p>This app has auto-download and auto-delete. It's unable to auto-download oldest to newest, so I am not keeping it.</p>
<h2>Podkicker</h2>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ait.podka">Podkicker</a> is rated 4.2 stars on the google play store. It is ad-supported.</p>
<p>This app is hands-down the simplest UI for a podcast app of the four. Very intuitive, and easy to use, but the simplicity has its downsides, including making it harder to do some bulk tasks, but this was rather minor.</p>
<p>The app seems to lack an auto-delete, but it has a new-episodes-only auto-download. Goodbye app.</p>
<h2>Podcast Addict</h2>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bambuna.podcastaddict">Podcast Addict</a> is rated 4.6 stars on the google play store. It is ad-supported.</p>
<p>This podcast player has a bunch of features that I don't (and probably will never) use, such as playlists, and live streams. There are <em>a lot</em> of settings, but they start with pretty good defaults, so it's not an issue.</p>
<p>This was the only app I could find that would download from oldest to newest. I've set a limit of 10 auto-downloaded episodes per show, so I don't fill up my phone right away.</p>
<p>The UI is pretty good, and not too hard to figure out as you go. It also has silence skipping, which is sort of neat.</p>
<p>I'm really liking this app, and I got the <strong>Donate</strong> version. If you like the app, it's worth supporting the developer (and removing ads) by throwing a few bucks his way.</p>
<h2>You're so picky!</h2>
<p>Maybe you're saying, "one silly feature destroyed most of your options!"</p>
<p>I don't want to have to think about my podcast app. If I have to think about it, or manually download episodes before driving, then it's not doing it's job as well as it should.</p>
<h2>Bye</h2>
<p>I hope this helps you decide on a podcast app. Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speech for Michael and Elizabeth's Wedding]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/speech-for-michael-and-elizabeths-wedding</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/speech-for-michael-and-elizabeths-wedding">
        </link>
        <updated>2015-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a speech/poem/rap for my brother's wedding. The lyrics are as follows:</p>
<hr>
<p>Mi<strong>chael</strong> and Eli<strong>za</strong>beth, the new<strong>ly</strong> married cou<strong>ple</strong>,<br>
I'm <strong>ex</strong>cited for <strong>you</strong> both, yet it's <strong>sad</strong> to see you <strong>go</strong>.<br>
It <strong>has</strong> been really <strong>awe</strong>some having <strong>Mi</strong>chael as my <strong>bro</strong>,<br>
Here <strong>are</strong> some facts a<strong>bout</strong> him that you <strong>may</strong> or may not <strong>know</strong>:</p>
<hr>
<p>Mi<strong>chael</strong> is very <strong>car</strong>ing, and for <strong>that</strong> he is a<strong>dored</strong>,<br>
He's <strong>grac</strong>ious, and he's <strong>thought</strong>ful, and he <strong>seeks</strong> to please the <strong>Lord</strong>.<br>
Our re<strong>la</strong>tionship was<strong>n't</strong> a picture <strong>per</strong>fect story<strong>board</strong>,<br>
But o<strong>ver</strong> a little <strong>time</strong> it has most <strong>def</strong>initely <strong>soared</strong>.</p>
<p>"To <strong>have</strong> a good re<strong>lation</strong>ship with your <strong>wife</strong>, you must be <strong>nice</strong><br>
to <strong>your</strong> mom and your <strong>sis</strong>ters" our dad <strong>told</strong> us Dykstra <strong>guys</strong>.<br>
I've <strong>ob</strong>served that Mi<strong>chael</strong> has indeed <strong>foll</strong>owed that ad<strong>vice</strong>;<br>
He <strong>hugs</strong> Becky or <strong>mom</strong> of-ten; like <strong>each</strong> day, if not <strong>twice</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>Mi<strong>chael</strong> is a ge<strong>ner</strong>ous guy; he'd <strong>of</strong>ten volun<strong>teer</strong>,<br>
a<strong>round</strong> the house, at <strong>church</strong>, and es-sen<strong>tial</strong>ly any<strong>where</strong>.<br>
He'll <strong>stop</strong> by the road, <strong>to</strong> help a stran<strong>ger</strong> put on a <strong>spare</strong>.<br>
Him <strong>loan</strong>ing out his <strong>re</strong>sources is <strong>a</strong> common af<strong>fair</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>If</strong> the milk ran <strong>out</strong>, and mom said "<strong>Who</strong> wants to get <strong>more</strong>?"<br>
Of<strong>ten</strong> Michael would <strong>cheer</strong>fully go <strong>car</strong>ry out the <strong>chore</strong>.<br>
His <strong>sib</strong>lings' food was <strong>some</strong>thing he would <strong>ran</strong>domly pay <strong>for</strong>.<br>
He <strong>was</strong> the kind of <strong>guy</strong> who would o<strong>pen</strong> and hold the <strong>door</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>If <strong>you</strong> know Michael <strong>at</strong> all, then you <strong>know</strong> he's dili<strong>gent</strong>,<br>
and <strong>that</strong> he likes to <strong>make</strong> sure that all <strong>his</strong> time is well <strong>spent</strong>.<br>
After <strong>a</strong> short obser<strong>va</strong>tion, a stran<strong>ger</strong> made the com<strong>ment</strong><br>
that <strong>he</strong> wished he could <strong>have</strong> Michael un<strong>der</strong> his employ<strong>ment</strong>.</p>
<p>He <strong>stu</strong>dies for his <strong>school</strong>, early be<strong>fore</strong> the sky is <strong>lit</strong>.<br>
He <strong>works</strong> quickly when <strong>on</strong> the job and <strong>he's</strong> not counter<strong>feit</strong>.<br>
I <strong>know</strong> this because <strong>at</strong> home he does <strong>not</strong> just like to <strong>sit</strong>.<br>
He <strong>sees</strong> work that needs <strong>to</strong> be done, and <strong>pro</strong>ceeds to do <strong>it</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>So <strong>as</strong> you both ac<strong>com</strong>plish this mi<strong>le</strong>stone of life's <strong>race</strong>,<br>
it <strong>is</strong> my prayer that <strong>God</strong> will give you <strong>His</strong> amazing <strong>grace</strong>.<br>
Un<strong>til</strong> the day you <strong>pass</strong> away, and <strong>stand</strong> before God's <strong>face</strong>;<br>
put <strong>God</strong> first, then your <strong>spouse</strong> second, and <strong>your</strong>self in third <strong>place</strong>.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FLL]]></title>
        <id>http://josephdykstra.com/fll</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/fll">
        </link>
        <updated>2014-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was on a <a href="http://www.firstlegoleague.org/">First Lego League</a> team, the <a href="http://datadragons.com/">Data Dragons</a> for 5 years.</p>
<p>First Lego League (FLL) is a program designed to teach students about science and technology. Each team researchs a problem, creates a solution, and presents it to the judges at a competition. They also create a LEGO Mindstorms robot, and program it to do missions on a 4 ft. x 8 ft. table. Whoever scores the most points gets an award, whoever has the best presentation gets an award, etc.</p>
<h3>What I learned</h3>
<p>I learned about basic robotics, mechanics, teamwork, and a little bit of programming.</p>
<h3>Team Acheivements (While I was on the team)</h3>
<ul>
<li>2008: Climate Connections
<ul>
<li>Regionals: 1st Place Teamwork</li>
<li>Iowa State: 2nd Place Programming</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2009: Smart Move
<ul>
<li>Regionals: 2nd Place Champions</li>
<li>Iowa State: 1st Place Champions</li>
<li>Nebraska State: (Unofficial) 2nd Place Robot Performance</li>
<li>Worlds: 3rd Place Research</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2010: Body Forward
<ul>
<li>Nebraska State: 1st Place Champions</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2011: Food Factor
<ul>
<li>Regionals: 1st Place Champions</li>
<li>Nebraska State: 3rd Place Champions</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>