<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>918c7751-68b6-7b8e-f1fe-37779d91fa11</id>
    <title>Joseph Dykstra&apos;s Blog</title>
    <updated>2016-01-31T03:54:59Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
        <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
        <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://josephdykstra.com"/>
    <subtitle>Follow Joseph&apos;s opinions on your feed reader!</subtitle>
    <logo>http://josephdykstra.com/logo.png</logo>
    <rights>Copyright © Joseph Dykstra 2015.</rights>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speech for Michael and Elizabeth's Wedding]]></title>
        <id>73d2d4bc-6ef0-b8b8-8536-0266606dfbf4</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/speech-for-michael-and-elizabeths-wedding">
        </link>
        <updated>2015-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a speech/poem/rap for my brother's wedding. The lyrics are as follows:</p>
<hr>
<p>Mi<strong>chael</strong> and Eli<strong>za</strong>beth, the new<strong>ly</strong> married cou<strong>ple</strong>,<br>
I'm <strong>ex</strong>cited for <strong>you</strong> both, yet it's <strong>sad</strong> to see you <strong>go</strong>.<br>
It <strong>has</strong> been really <strong>awe</strong>some having <strong>Mi</strong>chael as my <strong>bro</strong>,<br>
Here <strong>are</strong> some facts a<strong>bout</strong> him that you <strong>may</strong> or may not <strong>know</strong>:</p>
<hr>
<p>Mi<strong>chael</strong> is very <strong>car</strong>ing, and for <strong>that</strong> he is a<strong>dored</strong>,<br>
He's <strong>grac</strong>ious, and he's <strong>thought</strong>ful, and he <strong>seeks</strong> to please the <strong>Lord</strong>.<br>
Our re<strong>la</strong>tionship was<strong>n't</strong> a picture <strong>per</strong>fect story<strong>board</strong>,<br>
But o<strong>ver</strong> a little <strong>time</strong> it has most <strong>def</strong>initely <strong>soared</strong>.</p>
<p>"To <strong>have</strong> a good re<strong>lation</strong>ship with your <strong>wife</strong>, you must be <strong>nice</strong><br>
to <strong>your</strong> mom and your <strong>sis</strong>ters" our dad <strong>told</strong> us Dykstra <strong>guys</strong>.<br>
I've <strong>ob</strong>served that Mi<strong>chael</strong> has indeed <strong>foll</strong>owed that ad<strong>vice</strong>;<br>
He <strong>hugs</strong> Becky or <strong>mom</strong> of-ten; like <strong>each</strong> day, if not <strong>twice</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>Mi<strong>chael</strong> is a ge<strong>ner</strong>ous guy; he'd <strong>of</strong>ten volun<strong>teer</strong>,<br>
a<strong>round</strong> the house, at <strong>church</strong>, and es-sen<strong>tial</strong>ly any<strong>where</strong>.<br>
He'll <strong>stop</strong> by the road, <strong>to</strong> help a stran<strong>ger</strong> put on a <strong>spare</strong>.<br>
Him <strong>loan</strong>ing out his <strong>re</strong>sources is <strong>a</strong> common af<strong>fair</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>If</strong> the milk ran <strong>out</strong>, and mom said "<strong>Who</strong> wants to get <strong>more</strong>?"<br>
Of<strong>ten</strong> Michael would <strong>cheer</strong>fully go <strong>car</strong>ry out the <strong>chore</strong>.<br>
His <strong>sib</strong>lings' food was <strong>some</strong>thing he would <strong>ran</strong>domly pay <strong>for</strong>.<br>
He <strong>was</strong> the kind of <strong>guy</strong> who would o<strong>pen</strong> and hold the <strong>door</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>If <strong>you</strong> know Michael <strong>at</strong> all, then you <strong>know</strong> he's dili<strong>gent</strong>,<br>
and <strong>that</strong> he likes to <strong>make</strong> sure that all <strong>his</strong> time is well <strong>spent</strong>.<br>
After <strong>a</strong> short obser<strong>va</strong>tion, a stran<strong>ger</strong> made the com<strong>ment</strong><br>
that <strong>he</strong> wished he could <strong>have</strong> Michael un<strong>der</strong> his employ<strong>ment</strong>.</p>
<p>He <strong>stu</strong>dies for his <strong>school</strong>, early be<strong>fore</strong> the sky is <strong>lit</strong>.<br>
He <strong>works</strong> quickly when <strong>on</strong> the job and <strong>he's</strong> not counter<strong>feit</strong>.<br>
I <strong>know</strong> this because <strong>at</strong> home he does <strong>not</strong> just like to <strong>sit</strong>.<br>
He <strong>sees</strong> work that needs <strong>to</strong> be done, and <strong>pro</strong>ceeds to do <strong>it</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>So <strong>as</strong> you both ac<strong>com</strong>plish this mi<strong>le</strong>stone of life's <strong>race</strong>,<br>
it <strong>is</strong> my prayer that <strong>God</strong> will give you <strong>His</strong> amazing <strong>grace</strong>.<br>
Un<strong>til</strong> the day you <strong>pass</strong> away, and <strong>stand</strong> before God's <strong>face</strong>;<br>
put <strong>God</strong> first, then your <strong>spouse</strong> second, and <strong>your</strong>self in third <strong>place</strong>.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FLL]]></title>
        <id>a818f969-d87e-4b03-3fd8-0fefdda8aa56</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/fll">
        </link>
        <updated>2014-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was on a <a href="http://www.firstlegoleague.org/">First Lego League</a> team, the <a href="http://datadragons.com/">Data Dragons</a> for 5 years.</p>
<p>First Lego League (FLL) is a program designed to teach students about science and technology. Each team researchs a problem, creates a solution, and presents it to the judges at a competition. They also create a LEGO Mindstorms robot, and program it to do missions on a 4 ft. x 8 ft. table. Whoever scores the most points gets an award, whoever has the best presentation gets an award, etc.</p>
<h3>What I learned</h3>
<p>I learned about basic robotics, mechanics, teamwork, and a little bit of programming.</p>
<h3>Team Acheivements (While I was on the team)</h3>
<ul>
<li>2008: Climate Connections
<ul>
<li>Regionals: 1st Place Teamwork</li>
<li>Iowa State: 2nd Place Programming</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2009: Smart Move
<ul>
<li>Regionals: 2nd Place Champions</li>
<li>Iowa State: 1st Place Champions</li>
<li>Nebraska State: (Unofficial) 2nd Place Robot Performance</li>
<li>Worlds: 3rd Place Research</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2010: Body Forward
<ul>
<li>Nebraska State: 1st Place Champions</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2011: Food Factor
<ul>
<li>Regionals: 1st Place Champions</li>
<li>Nebraska State: 3rd Place Champions</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VEX]]></title>
        <id>25da7c7a-42fd-b53a-813c-81eb94f229d4</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/vex">
        </link>
        <updated>2014-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was on a <a href="http://vexrobotics.org">VEX</a> team, <a href="http://technapwn.com">TechnaPWN Robotics</a> for 2 years.</p>
<p>VEX was designed to teach students about STEM. (Science, Technology, Engineering, Math.) Students design, build, program, and drive a robot for each game, documenting their progress.</p>
<p>2013 was my first year, and I basically helped build the robot. I did some code maintainence, and some autonomous programming. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TUmyI8DoeQE">TechnaPWN Programming Skills 2013</a></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/TUmyI8DoeQE"></iframe>
<p>2014 was my last year. (As a student, that is. I do a bit of mentoring now.) I took a larger role in all areas; I designed and built more of the robot than I did the previous year, and I was the sole programmer. I was also the main driver, but could not have gone far without the coach and secondary driver. (Shout-out to y'all!) At the World Championship, we had issues, but were picked by <a href="http://youtu.be/QR0cl95RWIQ">Team 1200F</a>. We ended up losing in the Division Finals, in matches 2 and 3. Here is my favorite match: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YQccSPfuhW4">Division Finals Match 1</a></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YQccSPfuhW4"></iframe>
<h3>What I learned</h3>
<p>I learned about intermediate robotics, mechanics, and programming. It was also a good tool for learning to handle stress. :)</p>
<h3>Team Acheivements (While I was on the team)</h3>
<ul>
<li>2013: Sack Attack
<ul>
<li>Regionals: Tournament Champions at 5 of 7; various other awards</li>
<li>Nationals: 2nd Place Programming Skills, Division Finalists</li>
<li>Worlds: Innovate Award, 2nd Place Programming Skills</li>
</ul></li>
<li>2014: Toss Up
<ul>
<li>Regionals: various awards</li>
<li>Iowa State: 9-0-0, 1st Seed, Tournament Champions, Excellence Award</li>
<li>Nationals: 8-2-0, 2nd Seed</li>
<li>Worlds: 5-5-0, Division Finalists</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Résumé]]></title>
        <id>d616558b-4a78-db50-f4a9-2ec48957218b</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/resume">
        </link>
        <updated>2014-10-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Joseph Dykstra</h2>
<p><a href="mailto:josephdykstra@gmail.com"><em>josephdykstra@gmail.com</em></a></p>
<h2>About Me</h2>
<p>I am passionate about software development. I am ambitious, and have been writing code for over 5 years.</p>
<p>I like writing JavaScript modules, and websites.</p>
<p>I am currently working remotely for <a href="http://renweb.com">RenWeb</a>, a company that makes school-related software.  I fix issues that clients have, create custom reports, and develop new functionality.</p>
<h2>Objective</h2>
<p>I am not currently looking for work.</p>
<h2>Knowledge</h2>
<ul>
<li>Languages:
<ul>
<li>JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, ColdFusion, C</li>
<li>Written a little bit of Python, and BASIC</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Compilers/Runtimes:
<ul>
<li>Extensive use of NodeJS, RobotC, and GCC</li>
<li>Used Python, and MySQL a little bit</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Tools:
<ul>
<li>Sublime Text, Atom, Notepad++, SSMS, cmd, npm, TortoiseGit</li>
<li>Used terminal, Github for Windows, and SQLyog a little bit</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Operating Systems:
<ul>
<li>Windows XP - 8</li>
<li>Mac OS X</li>
<li>Ubuntu (GUI and CLI)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h2>Experience</h2>
<h3>RenWeb | April 2015 - [Present]</h3>
<p><a href="http://renweb.com">renweb.com</a></p>
<p>I work with a small team to fix issues that come in, and develop new features on software for over 3000 schools.</p>
<ul>
<li>I have created a label system so schools can print Mail Labels, ID Cards, barcodes, and more onto standard Avery label sheets.</li>
<li>I have worked with REST APIs to sync school data with 3rd party school-related software such as LMS's and State Reporting.</li>
<li>I work on fixing various issues. Few issues are like other issues. My debugging skills have improved a lot in this position.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Personal Projects | July 2008 - [Present]</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ArtskydJ?tab=repositories">Github Repositories</a> - <a href="http://npmjs.org/~artskydj">NPM modules</a></p>
<ul>
<li>I wrote <a href="http://justlogin.xyz/">Just Login</a>, an email-based authentication library for node.js servers</li>
<li>I have created hundreds of <a href="https://github.com/pulls?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=is%253Apr+author%253AArtskydJ+">pull requests</a> on Github to various open source projects</li>
<li>I wrote the <a href="https://github.com/ArtskydJ/josephdykstra.com">server code</a> for my <a href="http://josephdykstra.com/">website</a></li>
<li>I have written and I maintain over <a href="http://npmjs.org/~artskydj">50 JavaScript modules</a> for node.js</li>
<li>I wrote <a href="https://github.com/ArtskydJ/snake">Snake</a>, <a href="https://github.com/ArtskydJ/tetris">Tetris</a>, and an <a href="https://github.com/ArtskydJ/eight-queens">8-Queens Solver</a> in C</li>
</ul>
<h3>Well Rooted Gardens | May 16, 2014 - [Present]</h3>
<p><a href="http://wellrootedgardens.com">wellrootedgardens.com</a></p>
<p>I work part time for Well Rooted Gardens doing landscape work.  During the winter, we do snow removal.</p>
<h3>Coding in the Wild | October 2, 2013 - [Present]</h3>
<p><a href="http://github.com/coding-in-the-wild">github.com/coding-in-the-wild</a></p>
<p>Coding in the Wild is a group started by a professional developer.  He invited people who were interested in software development to learn development techniques.  We worked together to create a back-end node.js authentication module with an <a href="http://justlogin.xyz/">interactive website</a>.  Now we are working to create a chat room where users upload &amp; play their music for the group, in a round-robin fashion.</p>
<h3>TechnaPWN (VEX Robotics) | September 2012 - April 2014</h3>
<p><a href="http://technapwn.com">technapwn.com</a> - <a href="http://youtube.com/TechnaPWN">youtube.com/TechnaPWN</a></p>
<p>I wrote RobotC <a href="https://github.com/ArtskydJ/technapwn-toss-up">code</a> (based on C) for a VEX robot, including pre-programmed routines, teleoperation, slewed motor control, an extensive LCD menu system, and more.  I maintained and updated the code throughout the entire season.  Also, the previous year, I worked with two other team members to write and maintain the code-base.  I am now mentoring the team, although I am not on it.</p>
<h3>Data Dragons (FLL, LEGO Robotics) | September 2008 - February 2013</h3>
<p><a href="http://datadragonsfll.com">datadragonsfll.com</a></p>
<p>Being on this team taught me about teamwork and basic robotics.  The team took 1st place Robot Performance at Nebraska State in 2012.  I was a mentor for the team during the 2012-2013 season.</p>
<h2>References</h2>
<ul>
<li>Josh Duff
<ul>
<li><a href="http://joshduff.com">http://joshduff.com</a></li>
<li>Developer, <a href="http://www.edatasource.com/">eDataSource</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Tobias Davis
<ul>
<li><a href="http://davistobias.com">http://davistobias.com</a></li>
<li>Developer, <a href="http://www.edatasource.com/">eDataSource</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Evan Hurd
<ul>
<li>Developer, <a href="http://www.renweb.com/">RenWeb</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Seth Dykstra
<ul>
<li>On-Site IT Support, <a href="http://www.pltechnology.com/">P&amp;L Technology</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>David Dykstra
<ul>
<li>Owner of Millennium Construction (Omaha)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Michael Dykstra
<ul>
<li>Apprentice plumber, Schulte Plumbing</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change | 2]]></title>
        <id>5d79dba4-3b13-666d-0fe1-48e2f00ebc93</id>
        <link href="http://josephdykstra.com/change-pt-2">
        </link>
        <updated>2014-02-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>People tend not to welcome change, even good change. (Think about every time Facebook updates its interface.)</p>
<p>People don't want to change themselves, they like routine, they like order.</p>
<p>In football, the successful teams get into a routine, (a rhythm, as some announcers call it,) and move the ball down the field methodically.</p>
<p>I like my current bedroom. It might not be in the most convenient place, but I would not want to get used to sleeping in a different room.</p>
<p>People don't want to change themselves, and do not like it when outside change requires them to.</p>
<p>I did not like it when my church switched tunes on 2 songs I liked. On one, I liked the new tune better, but I had gotten used to the old tune, and didn't like switching. On the other, I didn't like the new tune as well.</p>
<hr>
<p>Sometimes people do like change. They want a different job, just because it is different. They are tired of being slaves of routine. They don't like repeating the same task 2000 hours each year. (50 weeks * 5 days * 8 hours, 2 weeks vacation.)</p>
<p>This is why some people like going on vacation, <em>and</em> like coming home from vacation.</p>
<hr>
<p>If you are in a routine of serving the Lord, do not get tired of it!</p>
<p>If you are in a routine of not serving the Lord, do get tired of it!</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Dykstra</name>
            <email>josephdykstra@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>http://josephdykstra.com</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>